# **Austin Smith**

## Front End Developer

https://www.austinsmith.online/ austin.smith.ads@gmail.com \$\ 912-346-1349

## **Summary**

A Front End Developer with a focus on web-based technologies and experience across the stack. A background in advertising at a design school which translates to increased proficiency in UX/UI and front-end development.

Proficient in JavaScript, Python, SQL and constantly learning new programming languages and frameworks. Efficient problem solver that can look at things from unique perspectives. Works well on a team and loves learning new tips and tricks from others. To-do list includes learning C++ for game development.

### **Skills**



### **Projects**

05/2020 - 06/2020

#### Music-is-for-me ☑

- MERN full stack application that lets users find teachers/students to learn specific musical instruments.
- Worked on the front-end and UX/UI, state management with React hooks and created multiple components and pages.
- MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS. **Deployed App:** BIT.LY/MUSIC-IFM-APP ☑ **Github Repo:** BIT.LY/MUSIC-IFM-GIT ☑

04/2020 - 05/2020

#### Live Search 🗹

- Used JavaScript AJAX requests to query APIs with promises to request JSON from 2 different APIs. Users can search for their favorite food to find recipes and nearby restaurants with that specified searched food.
- Worked on wiring the Zomato API to show restaurants with recipes requested. (Zomato API is dysfunctional currently)
- Vanilla JavaScript

**Deployed App:** BIT.LY/LIVE-SEARCH-APP ☑ **Github Repo:** BIT.LY/LIVE-SEARCH-GIT ☑

01/2020 - 04/2020

#### Recoup 🗹

- Used Express and Node to run a server that uses Sequelize to generate data. Quickly navigate a lecture on a specific web development topic.
- Worked on JavaScript logic for extracting data from MySQL database.
- Sequelize, MySQL, NodeJS, JavaScript **Deployed App:** BIT.LY/RECOUP-APP ☑ **Github Repo:** BIT.LY/RECOUP-GIT ☑

## **Certificates**

#### Georgia Institute of Technology ☑

Full Stack Development - Certificate

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJs, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, & ReactJS.

## **Education**

## Savannah College of Art and Design, (SCAD) ☑

Savannah, GA

B.F.A. in advertising from a top design college in the United States.

## **Professional Experience**

12/2018 – present	Freelance Web Developer, Remote
	• Helped solve clients web development problems. Redeployed inaccessible website.
	Redesigned website layout.

• Engaged in web development consultations.

09/2018 - 11/2018 Intern, Global Team Blue (GTB) — Dearborn, MI

> • Designed prototype for Ford Motor Company using open data. Pitched prototype to their executives.

• Utilized open data to brainstorm different ideas before our group decided on a final prototype.

**Student,** Scad Collaboration with AARP (UX/UI Service Design) — Savannah, GA 05/2018

> • Helped create service design for AARP. • Pitched design in front of AARP executives.

### **Volunteering**

#### **Programming S.T.E.A.M. Workshop Teaching Assistant,** The Creative Coast

• Assisted teacher in helping students make their own video games using the web based game engine Construct 3. Facilitated by WWLaw Center, City of Savannah Live Oak Public Libraries. Funded by The Creative Coast.

#### Tutor/Coach, Codebar

• Tutoring students on programming concepts through Discord.